WILLIAN SILVA

Software Developer

CONTACT

(514) 772-2504

williande.silva@yahoo.ca

github.com/WillianGust

www.linkedin.com/in/silvawill/

EDUCATION

Bootcamp

2023

Intensive Ruby advanced learning

Collège Ahuntsic

2021

AEC in Transactional Web Development

Oswaldo Cruz University

2007

B. S. Chemical Engineering*

* Equivalence issued by the Ministère du Québec (MIDI) in 2010

SKILLS

- Ruby, PHP
- Git
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Docker
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL
- Linux environment
- AWS, Azure
- Agile, Scrum
- Rest APIs

VOLUNTEERING

Coach

CSL Longueuil | 2023 Soccer coach for children aged 7 to 8. Interaction and management of their activities.

PROFILE

Software developer with backend focus, experience in integrations, unit testing, and API integration. Earned an engineering qualification an AEC in programming, along with extensive industry experience, including 2 year as a programmer. Determined to leverage more experience and improve programming skills within a creative team as a developer, as well as create unparalleled value in this field.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PROGRAMER ANALYST

M2i3 Inc

Oct 2021 - Mar 2023

Develop and improve user interfaces with full stack engineer. Contribute to create interfaces with RoR, SilverStripe. Develop backend with Active Records and SQL queries, streamlines with Docker compose. Conduct tests with Minitest. Organize and reuse display logic in Rails applications within the cells ecosystem. Code refactoring in front-end and back-end, ActiveStorage configuration, and JavaScript for uploading images to the server. Coding the translation via locales and input authentication with REGEX. Proficiency in PHP, CRM, and ERP. Server requests and database queries for the presentation of informative customer tables. Customer reports and integration with the UPS platform.

OTHERS EXPERIENCES

R&D CHEMIST

Industries Pépin Ltd

2018 - 2021

Chemist responsible for water-based paint

R&D CHEMIST

Evotech ind.

2016 - 2018

Chemist and deputy to the R&D manager